A Guide to the Northrop Grumman Contract Records of the Virginia Information Technologies Agency, 2004-2019
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Northrop Grumman Contract Records of the Virginia Information Technologies Agency, 2004-2019
The Library of Virginia
53613
3 cu. ft. (3 boxes)
Virginia Information Technologies Agency
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 53613 transferred by the Virginia Information Technologies Agency, 5 May 2022.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Virginia Information Technologies Agency (VITA) was approved by the General Assembly on 2 April 2003 during Governor Mark R. Warner's administration to provide information technology that enables the government to better serve the public. VITA serves as the Commonwealth's consolidated, centralized information technology organization. The newly created agency superseded the Department of Information Technology and the Department of Technology Planning. Its responsibilities include the operation of information technology infrastructure for the executive branch agencies, the governance of information technology investments, and the procurement of technology on behalf of other state agencies and institutions of higher learning. The Information Technology Investment Board (ITIB) was created along with VITA to review and prioritize enterprise-wide technology investments across state government. The Board is also responsible for appointing the Chief Information Officer (CIO) to serve as VITA's chief administrative officer.
Responsibility for the 911 Services Board and the Virginia Geographic Information Network Advisory Board was transferred from VITA to the Virginia Dept. of Emergency Services in 2020 (HB 1003, Chap. 423, approved March 23, 2020).
Chief Information Officers include: Lemuel C. Stewart, Jr., 2003-2009; Samuel Nixon, Jr., 2010-2015; Nelson P. Moe, 2015-2020.
Scope and Content
Northrop Grumman Contract Records, 2004-2019, consists of 3 boxes and are arranged in original order. These records document the administration of the VITA contract with Northrop Grumman. Includes Corrective Action Plans, 2009; Correspondence, 2007-2019; Independent Accountants' Reports, 2007-2017; Reports of Controls Placed in Operation and Tests of Operating Effectiveness, 2006-2017; Confidential Security Audits (RESTRICTED), 2007-2010; Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement, 2005-2006; and various other reports and plans related to the transition and deliverables.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the original order.
Contents List
- History files, 2004-2019.
  - Northrop Grumman (NG) Corrective Action Plan (CAP) - Book 1, 2009 Aug 28. (Box 1)
  - Northrop Grumman (NG) Corrective Action Plan (CAP) - Book 2, 2009 Aug 28. (Box 1)
  - Northrop Grumman (NG) Corrective Action Plan (CAP) - Book 3, 2009 Aug 28. (Box 1)
  - Northrop Grumman (NG) Corrective Action Plan (CAP) - Book 4, 2009 Aug 28. (Box 1)
  - Northrop Grumman (NG) Corrective Action Plan (CAP) - Book 5, 2009 Aug 28. (Box 1)
  - Northrop Grumman (NG) Corrective Action Plan (CAP) - Book 6, 2009 Aug 28. (Box 1)
  - VITA / Northrop Grumman correspondence, 2007-2015. (Box 2)
  - VITA / Northrop Grumman correspondence, 2016 Jan-June. (Box 2)
  - VITA / Northrop Grumman correspondence, 2016 July-Dec. (Box 2)
  - VITA / Northrop Grumman correspondence, 2017 Jan-June. (Box 2)
  - VITA / Northrop Grumman correspondence, 2017 July-Dec. (Box 2)
  - VITA / Northrop Grumman correspondence, 2018 Jan-June. (Box 2)
  - VITA / Northrop Grumman correspondence, 2018 July-Nov. (Box 2)
  - VITA / Northrop Grumman correspondence, 2019 May-July. (Box 2)
  - VITA Large Agency Transition Workbook - Phase 1 Integration, 2004 June. (Box 2)
  - Event information and remarks for VITA-NG partnership announcement, 2005 Nov 14. (Box 2)
  - Interim Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA), 2005 Nov 14. (Box 2)
  - Interim Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA) - Interim Phase Work Plan, 2005 Dec 14. (Box 2)
  - Interim Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA) - Refined Transition Plan, 2006 Feb 13. (Box 2)
  - Information Technology Infrastructure Partnership (ITIP), 2006 May. (Box 2)
  - Northrop Grumman (NG) Readiness to Assume Responsibility for Current Operations, 2006 June 09. (Box 2)
  - Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA) - Detailed Transition Plan, 2006 June 16. (Box 2)
  - NG and VITA Partnership - Day One, 2006 July 10-11. (Box 2)
  - CH Transition Phase Conceptual Deliverables - Jan-June 2006 Final Version and Client Acceptance, 2006 Aug 26. (Box 2)
  - Gartner Relationship Performance Assessment (RPA) - Final Report, 2014. (Box 2)
  - Integris Reports - CIA Contract Review (Apr), Sourcing Options Report (Oct) and Final Recommendations Report (Nov), 2015. (Box 2)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche), 2007 Jul-2008 June. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 4 Financial Audit, 2009 July-2010 June. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 4 Operational Audit, 2010 Oct 19. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 5 - Financial Audit as defined by the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA), 2010 July-2011 June. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 5 - Operational Audit as defined by the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA), 2011 Oct 21. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 6 - Financial Audit as defined by the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA), 2011 July-2012 June. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 6 - Operational Audit as defined by the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA), 2012 Sept 20. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 7 - Financial Audit as defined by the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA), 2012 July-2013 June. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 7 - Operational Audit as defined by the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA), 2013 Oct 16. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 8 - Financial Audit as defined by the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA), 2013 July-2014 June. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 8 - Operational Audit as defined by the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA), 2014 Oct 13. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 9 - Financial Audit as defined by the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA), 2014 July-2015 June. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 9 - Operational Audit as defined by the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA), 2015 Oct 29. (Box 3)
  - Independent Accountants' Report on Applying Agreed-Upon Procedures (Deloitte and Touche) - Contract Year 11 - Financial Audit as defined by the Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement (CIA), 2016 July-2017 June. (Box 3)
  - Report on Controls Placed in Operation and Tests of Operating Effectiveness (DTL), 2006 July-2007 June. (Box 3)
  - Report on Controls Placed in Operation and Tests of Operating Effectiveness (DTL), 2007 July-2008 June. (Box 3)
  - Report on Controls Placed in Operation and Tests of Operating Effectiveness (DTL), 2008 July-2010 June. (Box 3)
  - Report on Controls Placed in Operation and Tests of Operating Effectiveness (DTL), 2010 July-2011 June. (Box 3)
  - Report on Controls Placed in Operation and Tests of Operating Effectiveness (DTL), 2011 July-2012 June. (Box 3)
  - Report on Controls Placed in Operation and Tests of Operating Effectiveness (DTL), 2012 July-2013 June. (Box 3)
  - Report on Controls Placed in Operation and Tests of Operating Effectiveness (DTL), 2013 July-2014 June. (Box 3)
  - Report on Controls Placed in Operation and Tests of Operating Effectiveness (DTL), 2014 July-2015 June. (Box 3)
  - Report on Controls Placed in Operation and Tests of Operating Effectiveness (DTL), 2015 July-2016 June. (Box 3)
  - Report on Controls Placed in Operation and Tests of Operating Effectiveness (DTL), 2016 July-2017 June. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Corrections, 2007 Nov. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Health, 2007 Nov. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Juvenile Justice, 2007 Nov. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Motor Vehicles, 2007 Nov. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Social Services, 2007 Nov. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Taxation, 2007 Nov. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Transportation, 2007 Nov. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - VITA Central Operations, 2007 Nov. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Corrections, 2008 Apr. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Health, 2008 Apr. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Juvenile Justice, 2008 Apr. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Motor Vehicles, 2008 May. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Social Services, 2008 Apr. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Taxation, 2008 June. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Transportation, 2008 May. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - VITA Central Operations, 2008 Apr. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Alcoholic Beverage Control, 2009 Oct. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Corrections, 2009 Oct. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Health, 2009 Oct. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Motor Vehicles, 2009 Oct. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Social Services, 2009 Oct. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Taxation, 2009 Oct. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Transportation, 2009 Oct. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - VITA Central Operations, 2009 Oct. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Perimeter Center, 2010 Sept. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Social Services, 2010 Sept. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - Dept. of Transportation, 2010 Sept. (Box 3)
  - Confidential Security Audit Report (DTL) - VITA Central Operations, 2010 Sept. (Box 3)